A typhoon is coming to the Japanese archipelago.
Due to the typhoon, a large amount of seawater is pushed to the land,
causing devastating damage to the city.
Takassio.
The only thing that is safe that Tokyo and Osaka are safe
The battle with Takashio is behind the development of the big city
There are many surprising infrastructures created to protect our lives
24 hours and 365 days
I have to be within 30 minutes from the center
What?
We also went to the front line of the Takashio disaster prevention site
What is the revolutionary technology that automatically stops Takashio?
It's a disaster!
Let's learn about the disaster in Takashio!
Oigaimisan! Yeah!
Let's start the lesson!
Thank you! The theme of this lesson is... Let's start the lesson. Let's start.
The theme of this lesson is...
Takashio.
I've heard of it.
I'm not familiar with the word, but I'm more familiar with the word than the word that has appeared so far.
It's a little far.
But this is a very scary thing. Takashio is a phenomenon in which a typhoon comes and the sea surface rises very high and the sea water pushes the land at once.
So, if you imagine it, it's almost the same as a tsunami.
It's like a tsunami.
The sea water flows in and destroys the city. The reason why the sea level rises in a typhoon is because the typhoon is low-pressure.
So it has the power to pump up the sea water from the sea to the vacuum.
It rises and rises and rises.
And typhoons blow very windy, right? The wind blows, so the wind blows and the water level rises.
It looks like it's going to be very strong.
And the effect of the wind is stronger in the deep part of the bay.
That means the deepest part of the bay is the deepest part of Okuma.
This is the most dangerous area.
This area has a low altitude.
The water level is very low.
It is a zero-meter area.
If the water goes beyond the low altitude, it flows in at once.
The water will remain used up and become a waste.
It will cause a lot of damage.
If the road of typhoon and salt is the worst scenario,
the water damage caused by Takashio in Tokyo Bay is actually 110 trillion yen.
110 trillion yen
It is expected to be a rare hazard, which is 3.8 times the size of the Great East Japan Earthquake
Furthermore, in the terrain where Osaka and Nagoya are located deep in the bay,
It is at a great risk, just like Tokyo.
The only thing that makes Tokyo and Osaka safe is that they were lucky.
So, how do we protect the city from Takashio?
Human beings have been trying to find the answer.
First, we will learn from the measures we have taken so far.
The first mission is this. Let's investigate the history of the battle between Tokyo and Takashio.
Yes.
Tamai-kun will be in charge of this mission.
Are you ready?
Yes, I'm ready.
Thank you.
This time, there are four missions prepared by Instructor Fujii.
Each member will report the results.
First, Tamai will investigate the American War in the dream of a new marriage trip.
As the teacher said, Tokyo, which is weak to the terrain and Takashio, has been exposed to many of its damage.
First, please look at this.
This is a record of the typhoon that hit Tokyo during the Edo period.
A huge typhoon swallowed the city and caused the largest flood in Japan, with a total of 100,000 people dead in one episode.
But it was originally such a the damage is more severe.
So, we've taken some measures against Takashio.
First, this.
This is a stone wall called the Nami-oke no Hi
which is left at Susaki Shrine in Kiba, Koutou-ku.
This place was built during the Edo period.
It's still here.
There's a stone.
The Baku family bought 5,500 pots near the sea, which were attacked by Takashio.
It was forbidden to live here.
If you look at the floating painting at that time, you can see that there are no people living here.
This is a stone wall.
The first Takashio Taishaku was basically not to be built.
Next, let's look at another picture of the Susaki Shrine.
What? If you look at this picture, this is Shusaki Shrine, but if you look closely, you can see that there is a stone wall here.
When the damaged shrine was rebuilt, the land was built up.
If Takashio comes again, he will create a place to evacuate.
When Takashio came, he made a place to evacuate.
And another measure to avoid the tsunami was
the Bocho-tei, which is a dam set up along the coast to prevent the tsunami.
Bocho-tei is a dam set up installed on land to prevent the damage of tsunami and tsunami.
By stopping or delaying the intrusion of seawater into the city,
it is essential to prevent damage.
From the Edo period to the Meiji period, the east side of Arakawa,
on the coast of Kasai, in the Edo region,
there was a large business, about 4 km long,
and a dam was built.
It was like this that Takashio and his friends fought each other for a long time.
In the end, Takashio always won and continued to suffer a lot.
The typhoon that occurred in 1949 after the war was a big one.
The typhoon was called Kitty typhoon.
It's not that cute.
It's cute when you hear it.
It's a when you hear it. It's Kitty. At that time, typhoons were named after women.
So it's a cute name.
But it's actually a terrifying name.
Takashio, who climbed over 3 meters, was attacked by a typhoon.
The Edo River was destroyed and the city was flooded.
A large disaster that affected one-third of the residents occurred.
If there was nothing here, it would have been a city.
It says station.
Everyone is on a ship.
From this experience of the Kitty typhoon, Tokyo started the construction of a 5.3m high fire-resistant coastal dam was started.
The dam was built in 1951 and in 1957, a strong 4.5km long dam was completed.
I thought that the fire would be protected by this dam.
But it's not.
There will be a new problem.
Please see this photo.
This is a picture of the KASAI coastline that remains now.
You can see that the height is two steps.
In fact, the first low-height kitchen knife was made.
Later, I attached a higher kitchen to the low-cutting point we made earlier.
So, it wasn't enough?
Yes, it wasn't enough. But we made something really expensive at that time.
In fact, there is a problem that has to do with the unity of this area.
The reason is the deterioration of the ground.
Oh, on the contrary. Yes, the ground. The evolution of the ground is caused by the rise of the underground water.
The ground around the area is rapidly evolving.
In a terrible place, the ground has fallen by 4.5 meters.
The evolution of the ground in Tokyo was very intense.
4.5 meters is a lot.
It's more than our heart. It's true.
The ground was sinking year by year.
Every time, they had to raise the bar and survive.
Finally, there was a physical limit to the emergency surgery.
So, Tokyo-to
as a fundamental measure
set up a large-scale project as a fundamental measure.
The project is to build a house with a roof!
The area of the Tokyo Dome is 380 hectares, which is about 80 of the area. This is a plan to build a completely new city outside the city we live in.
It's a very difficult project.
It took 32 years from 1972 to 2004.
It's a huge project.
Have you ever been to Kasai Rinkai Park, right? Yes, we have!
That park was built from scratch to preserve the natural environment and landscape of Tokyo Bay.
I see. This was originally an ocean. We're going to make a new kitchen counter in this new area.
Here is the infrastructure!
This kitchen counter was made in the fire-resistant building business.
There is a certain technique to prevent the beautiful view from being damaged.
What is it?
This is a kind of kitchen that is made to protect the view of the view. This picture is hidden somewhere.
Can you find it?
You can see it nearby.
Nearby?
Excuse me. This? Near? Yes. Excuse me.
It's your first time, right?
You come here.
This. I thought so, too.
Just this?
This?
Here?
Can you avoid the waves with this?
It's difficult just there.
This?
This is a canoe made by the Tokyo Olympics.
It's not a cutting point. This is a cutting point by the Tokyo Olympics. It's not a cutting board.
This is a cutting board that looks like a tree.
But the whole thing is green.
It's a good line.
But Arlene is going to a very good line.
You're already looking at it, right?
I'm looking at it. I'm looking at it a lot.
But please look at it with a wider view.
Look at the whole thing.
A great hint is that it may be difficult to say that this is it.
All of them.
Where is it all?
All of Kasai Rinkai Park is...
a
Please sit down. All of Kasai Rinkai thing is a Masai Rinkai Park With soil, they build a safe hill and place the pole in the forest
Under the park with natural slope
there is a super strong
climbing pole which is 8m higher than Manchou
Without seeing the climbing pole,
people can build a place that people to enjoy the sea.
Wow!
If you go near the beach, you can see the high-rise buildings.
Yes, you can see the sea from the high-rise buildings.
That's why the sea is so beautiful.
And this invisible By putting soil on the ground, it becomes a safe and safe hill that is hard to break even in high tide.
Have you ever heard of the word Super-Tail?
No?
Not really.
It doesn't really make sense.
In fact, the tail that is made with the image of a fire is called Super-Tail.
It is also called High-Depth-Tail.
It is called a super-thin bar.
Super-thin bar is a bar that is used to gently lift the inside of the bar and function as a bar for the entire area.
Even if the water goes beyond the bar, it can reduce the damage to the minimum by gently flowing the slope.
So, there are many places are there now? The project is now a river. It is the leading water-based water system in Japan.
As you can see, there are two features.
It is perfect safety.
It is a never-breaking dam.
It is a park.
It is a rich living space that is familiar to water.
This is the highest achievement of modern geological technology.
It is an invisible
expansion system that was born at the end of the battle between Tokyo and Takashio.
It will be an important infrastructure to protect the lives of the people
Next mission
Let's investigate the front line base of Tokyo's Takashio
The person in charge of this mission is Momota
Did you check it thoroughly? Yes, please leave it to me
The person to investigate is Mom newly married Mamota with a happy aura.
Thank you for waiting.
The elite Infra warrior Mamota has returned.
Sorry, what?
Elite?
Last time, I was not there, so the correct answer was low.
Really?
I heard that it was hard. I heard that it was very high. It was hard.
I heard it was very expensive.
It was smooth.
I said it was excellent.
Everyone is excellent.
Do you know what other is inside the barrier?
I don't know
Other than the barrier?
Like a tetrapod?
Yes, a tetrapod
Here it is
It's a land gate and a water gate
It's like this
It blocks the part that the barrier can't be made with roads and
concrete, and it becomes a wall to block Takashio
I see
The land gate that blocks the road is usually open so that people and cars can pass through.
But it only closes when the water comes in and prevents water from entering.
I'm not used to it.
The water gate is installed on the floor.
It is also very important to protect the gills when the water comes in.
I often see this.
That's right.
No matter how high the height of the The doors are usually up and down, but there are also unique ones.
Ta-da!
It's cool!
The water gate is made of earth, so it can be higher than the normal door type.
It can be opened.
You can pass through a bigger ship.
What did you just say, Samae-san? How do you close it? You can get a bigger boat. What did you say?
How do I close it?
Good question!
I'm curious.
Like this?
Please guess.
No.
Like this?
It doesn't have to be like this.
It's okay. Like this! That's good.
Like this!
Now, let's see how it will end.
Here it is.
Oh!
I really want you to stop.
Oh, it's the first time.
It's the first time.
It's a surprising move. - Wait, wait. - Watergate is an important part of Tokyo.
The Tokyo Port has 15 water gates that protect the city from the high tide.
This time, we have entered the front line base of the high tide control center that manages the water gate.
The peach-colored infrastructure, Z!
We came to the high tide control Center in Koto-ku, Tokyo. Wow, it's so cool!
We had Mr. Muraoka, the director of the center, guide us.
This is the central control room of the Takashio Control Center.
It controls 15 water gates in Tokyo Port and controls the water level of the water tank. For example, this is the control room for the Tatsumi water gate in 15 locations and do the control of the waterway.
For example, this is the control tower of the Tatsumi water gate.
We check if the ship is sailing and then we operate the water gate.
Normally, when the water gate is over 2.3 meters, we close the water gate.
However, in the case of a typhoon, a rapid rise is predicted, so if you look at safety and it is 1.85, you will close the water gate.
To protect the city from the typhoon, it is necessary to make a precise judgment such as earlyphoons and earthquakes is also activated by special shifts in preparation for the lack of events.
Up to 70 employees are in 24-hour positions.
Thank you very much.
There are so many people because there are 70 people.
Only 24 hours.
We prepare a house for the staff in the site and a time limit of 30 minutes. We have a time limit of 30 minutes.
We have a time limit of 30 minutes.
We have a time limit of 30 minutes. We have a must stay within 30 minutes from the center.
Then I can't go on a trip?
You can't go shopping.
Shopping in the city is no good.
You can't go to your favorite sauna.
I can't go to the sauna for 30 minutes.
You must have a cell phone with you.
You can't go to the sauna.
Since the president was appointed, we've been holding back since the president was appointed.
I want to change it for about a day.
It's kind, but I'm worried.
I think we should close it and go out. Thank you. Takashio Countermeasures Center, where the director and staff work hard,
manages not only the water gate, but also the building next to it.
This is an important facility when closing the water gate.
It is a facility that does not cut off even if the water gate is cut off.
Then, here about the infrastructure.
This facility is controlled by the Takashio Control Center.
It plays an important role in the process of closing the water gate.
What is its role?
What is the role of this facility, which is active during the closing of the water gate?
When the water gate is closed?
Is there anything else to do?
When it's open, it's a reverse
I don't need it
I'm taking a break
But if the water gate is closed, it means that the water is flowing
Tamari-san, please be careful
Sorry
I've said it many times.
I was in danger.
I think you said about 50% of it.
It is a solution to the problem that occurs when the water door is closed.
What kind of problem occurs when the water door is closed?
Problems occur.
If the water door is closed, the water will not flow to the other side.
It means that you send the water to the other side gently.
It means that you are excited and hit the other side.
Let's see the correct answer.
When the water door is closed, the water inside will rise due to the rain.
It is a pump system that forcibly drains the water into the sea.
I see.
The correct answer is to drain the river in the water gate.
You came closer with a small speed.
That's right.
I was about to come closer after the start.
I was really nervous.
If you close the water gate, it means that a typhoon is coming.
There is a risk that the water level in the sea will rise and push it.
But because of the typhoon, it is raining heavily in Joryu River.
A lot of river water is flowing.
That is the cause of the risk of flooding.
That's right.
So if you don't drain the water, you can't prevent flooding at the same time as preventing high tide.
That's why we drain the water.
It is an important role.
Yes.
In this Tatsumi wastewater plant, the water of the can pump water into the sea at a very high speed.
Wow, every second?
I can't imagine every second.
Wow.
Two drain pumps are installed in Tokyo Port.
Even if all 15 water pipes are closed, the sea of ​​snow is not affected.
Wonderful.
Takashio Taisaku's frontline base, Takashio Taisaku Center.
In 2015, the second Takashio Taisaku Center was opened.
Even if one center is in a pinch, they are in a perfect position to operate the entire water gate from the other side.
Due to the lack of such iron walls,
Takashio, the 19th typhoon, which has seen the largest amount of rain in the history of observation in various countries, is also a solid block.
I closed the water gate once at 9clock just before the typhoon passed.
I opened the water gate once after the typhoon passed.
I saw a rise in the tide in TOKYO WAN.
I closed the water gate again at 4 o'clock after the typhoon passed.
I opened the water gate about two hours after the tide went down.
It is important to open the water gate.
The damage caused by the typhoon was zero.
That's amazing. The damage caused by Takashio was zero. Amazing!
The normal typhoon has only been used once to clear the water gate.
However, at this time, the city decided to close the gate again.
Because of the 24-hour system, the city of Tokyo was protected.
Takashio Countermeasures Center protects Tokyo from the damage of Takashio.
There was a professional who was able to make people's eyes shine 24 hours a day.
Interviewing the passionate feelings of young employees involved in the infrastructure.
Young infrastructure, yeah!
Kano Hattori, the third year of joining Zenecon.
What made you want him choose this industry?
My father was a construction worker.
Since I was a child, I've been taken to the bridge my father was approaching.
I was originally a neighbor, so I chose this industry.
Hattori, who followed his father and entered the construction industry.
She uses a shield machine to connect the sewerage facility in Shinjuku and Adachi.
I think that construction in places where people can't see is something only I can see the construction work in places where people can't see it, so it feels special and fun.
Hattori supports the life of the people of the city. What is your future goal?
I want to continue my career as a female employee, and I want to be one of the new candidates for female employees.
Go for it, young Infra players!
Next mission is to protect the ring from Takashio's new threat.
Sasaki will be in charge of this mission. Are you ready?
Yes, I'll do my best!
Sasaki is recently into sauna alone.
We have been preventing the damage of the Takashio River by various measures.
Do you know that there is a threat that has never been before?
Now?
I don't know.
Why?
Of course you know this word.
That is...
The global warming.
I see.
This problem is still very serious.
Please watch this video.
This is a simulation of temperature change from 1950 to 2100.
If you proceed to 2024, the temperature will rise by about 2 degrees and the red part will increase.
If we go back to 2100, it will be hot!
The whole earth will be red, or it will rise by about 4 degrees compared to 1950.
The problem is that the temperature rises, but the rise of the sea level rises by 4 degrees, the sea level rises by 39 cm. If the temperature rises by 4 degrees, the sea level rises by 71 cm.
It is designed to be.
If the sea level rises by 30 cm from now, more than half of the beach in Japan will be in the sea.
I have to take measures.
It's hard if the temperature rises 4 degrees
The problem is high tide
It is expected that the water level will rise and the waves will rise
Of course, even more dangerous things are expected
That is typhoon
The water vapor generated by global warming The low pressure is developing
The possibility of a large typhoon is being born one after another
The typhoon is getting worse in addition to the rise in the sea level
This is no longer an exaggeration to say that this is a water disaster in Japan.
Of course, in Tokyo Bay, which has a lot of 0m of sea level,
there are nine measures to prevent the warming.
In order to withstand the future high tide,
a plan is being proposed to build a fire pit.
We have investigated the construction site
Momoiro Infra
Juuuup
The construction of Takashio Taishaku is
located in Funabashi City, Chiba Prefecture
which is located in Tokyo Bay and has a 0m wide open space
It is constructed at a position of about 40 meters from the sea.
Nakamura-san from Chiba Port Office will guide you.
The construction has already begun.
First, he explained about the current facility.
This concrete wall is called a wall wall.
It was built about 50 years ago.
There is a facility where ships land on the sea.
If you can't build a dam on the coast,
The dam to be built on the land side is called a wall wall.
It is a plan to build a higher wall at a higher height.
The current height is about 2.4 meters from the ground, but we will make it 4.6 meters.
Assuming a typhoon that has worsened the climate change, the height required for the wall is 4.6 meters.
It may be good to just add concrete to the wall, but the wall here has a problem.
By shaking and liquidifying the ground with an earthquake, the wall may be tilted or sink.
When it was built 50 years ago, it was thought that it would be okay for earthquakes earthquake occurred by filling the large base of the wall.
However, when an earthquake occurs, the current wall is not useful.
I made it myself.
In fact, even in the Great East Japan Earthquake, a flood occurred near here.
Therefore, it is necessary to stabilize the wall so that it can withstand not only the walls, but it also makes the walls more stable.
Here is the infrastructure!
I knew it!
This construction solves the problem of liquidification while raising the walls.
What is this construction that solves all these problems?
Not only the height, but also the structure that is not even a big deal even if it is liquidified. What kind of structure is it?
It's difficult.
Yes, it's this flip.
It's a picture.
Ari often brings a picture.
Thank you. Thank pictures. Thank you.
Thank you.
What kind of construction?
If you want to rewrite it, there is still a spare.
Yes.
Let's think about it in a new way.
Oh, please.
Mom, you're good at this flip game.
Game!
It's a miracle. Wait a it. I'm good at it.
You've done it before, right?
It's not a game.
It's a game.
You've done it before, right?
Then, please announce the winner, Momota.
Ta-da!
Oh, your name is on it.
Something's on it.
I thought about it in a new way.
I thought I would add this.
This is liquid.
This is a propeller for liquidification.
This is a propeller.
I will write this.
I will not resist and match this.
I use this as it is.
We will combine them. We will use the same amount of energy. Yes. We will walk together.
If you are going to be liquid, I will be liquid.
You are a professional.
Tamae, please.
I will be liquid.
If you become liquid, you should harden it.
You are like Nakazu. you should harden it. Oh, I see. It's like Nakazu.
You should harden everything.
If you want to be a good carpenter, you should harden it from here.
Like concrete.
You mean to fill the soil with the same material as the table.
Yes, that's right.
If you use the same material, it will be stronger.
I see.
I think you can do it.
Takari, please.
I'm here.
This is...
Something over there.
I'm trying to settle on this soil.
When it's liquidified, it's going to be off.
I'm going to connect it to the sea.
That's why I'm here.
It's like a
It's like a It's like a with a learned one that was like a The hint is here. The wall is irrelevant.
Eh?
You said it first.
I said it first.
Then, we're going to lose this.
Yes.
First, we're going to make a new one.
Make a new one?
I'm going to rewrite it.
Is that okay?
I'm frustrated.
Make something new while preventing the original wall from getting in the way,
they make something new.
The answer is super simple.
It's simple, right?
I decided on it.
Like this?
Well, the white clothes go here.
The white clothesuba here.
Like this.
Okay, please announce the result, Momota-san.
Okay.
Like this?
Simple, the same thing.
Yes.
Side by side.
A little higher version.
Make it a little closer.
And if you connect Awa-yokuba here.
Is there any meaning to that? Connecting Awa-Yokuba here... Does that even make sense?
I thought it might not be strengthened.
I'm not good at drawing, but I'll make a vertical version of the water gate.
I'll build a pillar and make a kitchen knife that goes down from the top.
But the pillar will be liquidized at the pillar.
Yes, it will be liquidized.
Then, we will put the knife here.
In the water.
Takagi, please answer the last question.
I will make a very simple pillar.
I will make a strong pillar from the root.
Anyway, deep
Even if the surroundings become liquid, it doesn't matter
Let's see the correct answer
The material used for construction is a 11m long iron material
How will this be a wall? Start the construction!
First, we will hold the materials vertically with a crane.
It's Tamaji's.
Oh no, it's a water monster.
It's a water monster.
Then we will move it to the place where it will be installed.
It's here.
Then we will set it on the ground.
And then...
Huh?
Tomo!
It might be Reni-chan.
She's going to get stuck on the ground.
She's going to grab the top and hit it while vibrating.
Reni-chan!
She's going to loosen the body and reduce the resistance.
Relax my body?
The ball will hit the 11m ball at a speed of about 3 minutes.
It's so fast.
But this is not the end.
That's right.
The ball will be carried by a crane and attach it to the finished cloth.
And then...
Weld two pieces of cloth and make them into a long cloth with a length of 21.5 meters.
Can you do that again?
And then, attach the extended part of the cloth that again? And the stretched part is also punched in.
After this, the punch-in is completed.
The length of the wall is 21.5 meters.
About 17 meters are buried in the middle.
By the length of the wall,
Takashio can withstand the rain when it comes.
The point is this 17m depth.
As a result of the survey, it is thought that it will be liquidified.
It is about 15m deep.
By putting the material up to about 17m deep,
It will be a wall that can be liquidified.
I see. The bottom part is not liquidified.
I didn't know that.
So, Reiko is right! I see. The bottom part is not oxidized. I didn't know that.
But you are right!
Perfect!
The correct answer is to make a new wall by arranging the joints that are deep into the ground.
Great!
You are right.
You said to go as deep as possible.
Can Takashio master do it? Correct! You said you would go as deep as possible. Right?
I wonder if I can become a master of Takashio.
You suddenly can't get in the mood.
Suddenly you can't get in the mood.
Takashio Reni.
Compared to the current wall, it's so long.
That's why there was so much below.
That's right. It's a material that is painted.
I see.
The answer was to pierce.
What does it mean to pierce? Yes, it is. The answer is to put it in the tank. To put it in the tank?
If you do a water-repellent treatment, you can use this tank in a wide range.
It is also good for the reduction of yard space.
Since the sea is a rock where the ship is being boiled,
only the space for construction.
Therefore, it can be used with one crane by using a thin iron material.
Furthermore, it can be built adjacent to the old walls, so it can minimize the construction area.
After the
construction is over, the concrete will cover the entire structure.
Wow, that's a lot of work.
Wow.
Amazing.
It's so beautiful.
Right?
Since the old wall will cost a lot of money, we will leave it as it is, and fill the gap with the new wall with a stone, and then cover it with concrete to complete the structure.
The
Yuna-Bashi-Takashio disaster prevention business, which also supports the global warming, is scheduled to be completed in 2033.
10 years later!
It would be nice if we could proceed smoothly.
Given that the typhoon will be even bigger due to the global warming,
as long as we do not take these thorough measures against Takashio,
we will not be able to survive in Tokyo, Osaka, Nagoya, and other major cities.
Therefore, we will do our best to make Japan survive.
We will do our best to make Japan survive.
We will do our best to make Japan survive. We will do our best to make Japan survive. As long as we don't take measures to prevent the spread of the virus, we won't be able to survive in big cities like Tokyo, Osaka, and Nagoya.
So, we need to take thorough measures to survive in Japan.
Interviewing young employees' passionate thoughts on the infrastructure.
Young infrastructure, yeah!
We asked Mr. Miki Murase, the 5th year member of ZENECON.
She is the one who supplies gas from town to town in Ichihara City, Chiba Prefecture.
She is in charge of the reinforcement construction and supports the living infrastructure.
and supports the infrastructure of the house.
It's a source of energy. When I see my work being used in various places,
I feel happy when I realize that I was able to contribute to the project.
Ms Murase makes videos of her construction work
by herself. She makes videos of her own.
She introduces the charm of her business through her own songs. The reason is...
The construction industry has a strong image of the old days.
It's often called 3K.
But it's not said that it's 3K. But now that that's gone, I want young people and children to know the charm of construction.
I want to keep the construction industry going.
Go for it, Infra-senshi!
Now for the last mission is to investigate the evolving Takashio measures.
Takagi-kun is in charge of this mission. Have you been looking into it?
Yes, I've been looking into it.
When watching TV at home, Takagi is reacting like a wiper when watching TV at home.
We are continuing the evolution of Takashio measures that everyone has investigated.
First, please look at this.
What kind of role does this have?
I can imagine it somehow.
It's meaningless.
The name of this facility is. It doesn't make sense. This facility is called the Tsunami Barrier.
Barrier?
It means a barrier to stop water and waves that have come out so far.
I see. This is a barrier. This facility was originally developed to prevent tsunami If it continues, it will not only be dangerous to hit people and buildings, but also the current will block the road and cause the road to be blocked.
Therefore, this barrier is used to catch large currents without going against the waves with a simple structure.
It is a stute wire that can withstand 20 tons of force.
Between the sturdy stow, put a stow for energy absorption.
It has the role of a cushion that receives shock by transforming it.
It becomes a bain.
It's a very easy-to-understand exchange.
It's like a bain-marie.
In fact, even in the Great East Japan Earthquake, where many cars and ships were washed away,
the fish ship was stopped like this.
Not only does the current from the sea prevent the water from flowing into the city,
It's not only preventing the water from flowing into the city, but also preventing the car and port containers from leaking into the sea.
It's a barrier that reduces the amount of waste.
Currently, it's installed in 25 places nationwide.
Next, we have the land mine that Kanako-chan introduced us to the land gate.
The gate is a gate that locks the road and passage between the dam.
This gate is actually opened and closed by a power and electric power.
If this happens, you may not be able to get there in time or the electrical system may be damaged by water.
There are many people who need to operate.
A new land mine that solves such land mine issues has been developed.
What kind of thing is it? We have entered the development site.
Momoiro Infra Z.
I came to Sakai City, Osaka Prefecture.
I was guided by Nakayasu, a Hitachi Zosen.
This factory is equipped with a device that can simulate water damage in the city.
Wow.
This is a land-based flap gate.
When there is a flood or tsunami, it does not require power and does not require human operation.
It stops the flood.
Now, let's go to the infrastructure!
Why did you laugh?
I think it's a good angle.
You're pretty twisted today.
It's a twist.
A flap gate type landine that prevents high tide. This new device has a new method of automatic launch when high tide comes.
What is it?
What is the revolutionary mechanism of the new landmuhou that prevents the movement of the body?
I got it.
What?
You got it?
See, you got it.
Kawaii.
I got it.
Maybe.
Try it with your gestures.
I got it.
Maybe.
Try it with your gestures.
I got it.
Maybe.
Try it with your gestures.
Try it with your gestures. Try it with your gestures. Try it with your gestures. Try it with your gestures. Try it with your gestures. Ah... So, how does it move? How does it start moving?
How does it start moving?
It comes out with the power of water.
Yes, yes, I got it.
There are two sets on the right and left side, right?
Yes.
If you step on one side, the other side will come up.
Someone will step on one side, the other side will come up. Someone will step on it.
If you step on it, it's like a game.
The water goes into the open net.
If you jump out of the water with the momentum, it will come out.
It will come out.
It will be a round. It will rotate. Let's see to come out. It's going to come out. It's going to turn.
Let's see the correct answer.
Please give us the water.
It's not that close.
The water is flowing.
The water is coming.
It's coming. The water is coming. It's coming.
It's coming.
It's dangerous if it stays like this.
It's fast.
It's coming.
It's blocking the water.
As you can see, the gate is open even though it's not working.
The water is shut out. How can it be so fast? As you can see, the gate is open even though there is nothing in it.
How do you do this?
Amazing!
What is this system?
This door is 10cm thick.
When the tsunami comes, the water flows down.
When the water depth is about 5 cm, the door floats due to the water pressure.
It's heavy.
It's well thought out.
Water flows under the flap gate and the gate naturally rises due to the buoyancy.
It's buoyancy. The gate will naturally rise due to the force of the water. Oh, the force of the water. And the water pressure will push the gate up and prevent the water from sinking.
That's amazing!
So the correct answer is to use the power of water!
Each of you got almost the correct answer.
You were fast, Tamai-san.
You're really good, Tamai-san.
I knew that you would use the power of water.
When I heard the word flap, I could see it.
I had an image like this.
As expected of Tamai-san.
There is a secret to this rising movement.
If the gate is just used for powerlessness, the power of water increases when the propulsion is just opened, the water will be too strong and the gate will suddenly rise.
We are trying to avoid such movements.
The point is the weight attached to the gate.
The gate will rise safely by hanging the weight so that the brake is applied.
Wow.
and it will be able to stand up safely. Wow!
If you draw water, the gate will automatically be stored.
No one's hand is needed.
Wonderful!
It's really amazing!
There is a reason for the spread of this flap gate.
In the Great East Japan Earthquake,
firefighters were killed for water control. We are focusing on the equipment that does not require such operation in the future.
I think the biggest disaster is the rapid evacuation of people.
We are aiming for something that does not require any operation.
Currently, a flap gate-type land port is installed in 200 places nationwide.
In addition, the water gate uses this mechanism.
Put air in the gate and fix the stopper on the bottom.
By removing the stopper in an emergency, it floats and accepts the waves by taking off the stopper in an emergency.
Unlike the traditional water gate, the height of the boat is not limited.
Amazing!
It looks completely different.
Takashio measures will continue to evolve to protect the lives of people.
That's all for the investigation report.
Thank you, Minachu.
We have been building a town for hundreds of years.
But if a huge Takashio comes, it will be destroyed in one night.
It's not a waste of time.
If there is someone who works hard to build a city,
he has to put as much energy as building a city and work hard to prevent Takashio and disasters. and disaster prevention.
So it's important to build a city,
but it's also important to protect it.
I hope you learned a lot today.
Momoiro Infra Z.
The next theme is...
Tunnel!
The world-famous technology
hidden in the Seikan Tunnel The world's proud technology is thoroughly investigated
in the Seikan tunnel connecting Hokkaido and Honshu
The Great National Project has been established for 20 years
The latest technology for tunnel construction is also on air! On April 7th, Sunday, 11am, live on TV!
Please look forward to it!
Momoiro Infra Z is broadcasting with the cooperation of the partners you see here.
you